Leonard Wood Letters
Leonard Wood Letters
1871-1927
Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927.
13 letters (SC).
Correspondence of the Army officer, governor general of the Philippines. Outgoing letters, mostly written while Wood served in Cuba, and later in the Philippines.
149337
Biographical History
Leonard Wood (1860-1927) was a physician, soldier and United States military governor to Cuba and the Moro Province of the Philippines. Wood is best known for his work with the military and the Republican political party, his controversial governorship in the Philippines, and his relationship with Theodore Roosevelt. He also served as physician to several presidents, including William McKinley and Grover Cleveland.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Leonard Wood Letters consists of thirteen pieces of outgoing correspondence written between 1871 and 1927. Subjects include discussions about his philosophy of military service, the Moro conflict in Cuba, the politics and potential for economic development in the Philippines, and the death of Theodore Roosevelt.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Military history; Fallows, Edward Huntington, 1865-; Ackerman, Ernest A.; Smith, Alexander N.; Davenport, Henry J.; Greene, F. V. (Francis Vinton), 1850-1921.; Hickok, Paul Robinson, 1877-1945.; Maxwell, Perriton, 1868-1947.; Moses, George Higgins, 1869-1944.; Cuba -- Foreign relations -- United States.; Cuba -- History -- 1899-1906.; Philippines -- Economic conditions -- 1918-; Philippines -- Foreign relations -- United States.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Philippines -- Politics and government -- 1898-1935.; United States -- Foreign relations -- Cuba.; United States -- Foreign relations -- Philippines.; United States -- Insular possessions.; United States. -- Army -- Officers.; Letters (correspondence)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Marian, 25 Jan. 1871 (Sc 68)
  - Editor Independent, 29 Jan. 1902 (Sc 68)
  - Greene, Francis Vinton, 7 May 1904 (Sc 68)
  - Mr. Curtis, 12 Dec. 1904 (Sc 68)
  - Maxwell, Perriton, 29 Jun 1916 (Sc 68)
  - Hickock, Rev. Paul R., 19 Jan. 1919 (Sc 68)
  - Davenport, Henry J., 22 Jan. 1919 (Sc 68)
  - Sir, 3 Apr 1922 (Sc 68)
  - Moses, Sen. George H., 30 Mar. 1923 (Sc 68)
  - Smith, Alexander N., 26 Sep. 1923 (Sc 68)
  - Ackerman, Ernest R., 22 Oct. 1923 (Sc 68)
  - Fallows, Edward H., 11 Dec. 1926 (Sc 68)
  - Fallows, Edward H., 15 Mar. 1927 (Sc 68)